Guide to the Richard Pollay. Tobacco industry promotion (TIPS) collection, 1885-2012 and undated RL.11612
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Ephemera (Tobacciana), 1894-2002; undated; 13
  - Apparel--Hats, 1989-1992; undated; 177
    - Salem--White, sailboat logo, undated (Box E4)
    - Skoal Bandits--Skoal Bandit logo, National Tobacco Co. Limited, green and white, undated (Box E4)
    - Unknown--Formula racing insignia, blue, undated (Box E4)
    - Vantage--Vantage Championship, red visor, undated (Box E4)
    - Vantage--Vantage Cup Senior PGA Tour, white visor, undated (Box E4)
    - Vantage--Vantage Golf PGA Tour, white visor, undated (Box E4)
    - Winston--Eagle logo, red, undated (Box E4)
    - Winston--No Bull, black and tan, undated (Box E4)
    - Winston--The Wrap Only Winston Has It, black, undated (Box E4)
    - Winston--The Wrap Only Winston Has It, white, undated (Box E4)
    - Winston--Winston Cup 1989 Daytona 500, red and white (Box E4)
    - Winston--Winston Cup 1992 Daytona 500, red and white (Box E4)
    - Winston--Winston Eagle Racing, red, undated (Box E4)
  - Apparel--Shirts, 1987-1999; undated; 178
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--(Iraq War) Crosshairs, "I'd fly 10,000 miles to smoke a camel"; white, 1980s (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--Tobacco town, the smoker's destination; blue denim, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--American Cancer Society/Massachusetts Department of Public Health. Front: Youth Helping Youth Dis Tobacco; back: American Cancer Society Smoker's Quitline 1-800-try-to-stop, la linea dejalo 1-800-8-dejalo; white, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--D.A.R.E. to keep kids off drugs; black, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--No! Cigarette; tan/green/purple, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--Front: Tobacco Free; back: Trash your ash, Butt Out, St. Paul Tobacco Reduction Project; green, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--B.C. Council on Smoking and Health/B.C. Ministry of Health. Front: Thumbs Up! Thumbs Down! A program about tobacco use in the movies, Watch what you're watching; gray, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--Front: Endorsed by the Grim Reaper, Vancouver Cigarette Festival May 19-Oct. 10, 1999; back: de Murderer, multinational, Death Festival, Deadson & Wretches, Symphony of Tar, Slayer's Racing Team, http://airspace.bc.ca, (604) 444-8016; white (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--Front: Alaska High School Heroes, American Lung Association; back: smoking skull, Surgeon General's Warning: Smoking causes lung cancer, heart disease, emphysema, and may complicate pregnancy; black, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--Front: surgeons, Welcome to Tarboro Country, Generation Truth, www.generationtruth.net, (888) 50TRUTH; white, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--Front: Tobacco. Tumor causing, teeth staining, smelly, puking habit. Arizona Department of Health Services; black, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--Back: Camel/Oreo; Don't buy cookies from the house of cancer, STAT 1990; gray (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--D.A.R.E. to keep kids off drugs, Sponsored by Warren Electrical Contractors; blue, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--Front: Emphysema Slims, Throw tobacco out of sports, "Doctors Ought to Care" DOC, 5510 Greenbrier, Houston, TX 77005; white, undated (Box E5)
    - Anti-smoking, parodies, etc.--Front: American Cancer Society Great American Smokeout 10th anniversary; white, 1987 (Box E5)
    - Beech-Nut--Front: Beech-Nut softer & moister chewing tobacco; white, undated (Box E5)
    - Bucks--Front: Buck the System; back: Bucks with deer; white, undated (Box E5)
    - Capri--Front: Capri Super Slims; white, undated (Box E5)
    - Camel--Back: Camel 75th birthday! Camel. 75 years and still smoking. Joe Camel and pyramid; blue, 1988 (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Camel; back: Joe Camel in suit; yellow rain jacket, undated (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Camel; back: Camel smooth character, Joe Camel; white, undated (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Camel; back: A Pack of Camels, Joe Camel on motorcycle; white, 1990 (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Camel billiard ball; back: Joe Camel billiards; green, undated (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Camel football; back: Joe Camel sports fan; black, undated (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Camel genuine taste; back: Camel pyramid; white tank top, undated (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Camel groove blender; back: Camel big Vegas groove blender; white, undated (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Camel ampersand; back: Where it's @, black, 1997 (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Camel silhouette; back: camel eclipse, undated (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Club Camel member; back: Club Camel wish you were here; white, 1991 (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: The Hard Pack; back: Camel presents the hard pack, Joe Camel musician, white, 1991 (Box E6)
    - Camel--Front: Joe's beach club; back: Joe's beach club tell em Joe sent you; white, 1993 (Box E6)
    - Copenhagen--Front: Copenhagen Tough Co.; sleeve: U.S. Tobacco; back: Copenhagen Tough Co., Kokomo Havasu, Lake Havasau spring 1998; black, undated (Box E5)
    - Kool--Front and back Kool logo; white and green, undated (Box E6)
    - Kool--Front: Kool it fits; black, undated (Box E6)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro; back: Marlboro Wild West collection, Marlboro Man; black, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro; back: Penrod's on the beach; red, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro; red, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro; white, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro; white and red, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro; back: Marlboro Man silhouette; white, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro; back: Rodeo State Fair Sept. 26-Oct. 1, Gear for the Great Wide Open, finest quality, authentic wear, Marlboro Country Store; white, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro; back: Marlboro Man; white, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro Adventure Team; back: map "Lizard Rock, Outlaw Gap, Thunder Pass; white, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro Adventure Team; back: motorcycle; white, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro Adventure Team; back: truck; white, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro cigarette pack; white, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro, race car; back: Marlboro racing '92; white, 1992 (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro racing, checkerboard; back: Marlboro racing team; white, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro racing team, checkerboard; back: Marlboro racing team; red, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front and back: Marlboro racing Team Penske; white, undated (Box E7)
    - Marlboro--Front and back: Marlboro racing Team Roberts; white sweat shirt, undated (Box E8)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro Unlimited; back: Marlboro Unlimited Pipestone Pass, Three Forks, Grey Bull Basin, Horse Creek, Rock Springs, Trout Creek Pass; white, undated (Box E8)
    - Marlboro--Front: Marlboro World Championship Team; maroon, undated (Box E8)
    - Marlboro--Front: McLaren race car; white, undated (Box E8)
    - Marlboro--Front: Moto-Sport 11 June 1995, The first Alesi win Canadian Grand Prix 1995; back: Ferrari; white (Box E8)
    - Newport--Front: Newport; white, undated (Box E8)
    - Newport--Front: Newport; back: Newport, suspender design; white, undated (Box E8)
    - Newport--Front: Newport alive with pleasure; back: Newport; white and green, undated (Box E8)
    - Newport--Front: Newport alive with pleasure; white, undated (Box E8)
    - Newport--Front: Newport alive with pleasure; white and green, undated (Box E8)
    - Salem--Front: Everybocy's coming to the fresh side, Salem Fresh Wrap; back:, 1993 (Box E8)
    - Salem--Front: Salem; back: Salem fresh on the scene; black, 1990 (Box E8)
    - Salem--Front: Salem Fresh Wrap; back: Escape to the Fresh Side; white, 1992 (Box E8)
    - Salem--Front: Salem El Refrescante Tour; white, undated (Box E8)
    - Salem--Front: Salem SoundWaves refreshest new music; white, undated (Box E8)
    - Salem--Front: Salem the refreshest, sailboat, undated (Box E8)
    - Salem--Front: Shake it up, Salem the refreshest, champagne bottle; white, undated (Box E8)
    - Salem--Front and back: Salem fresh on the scene; black plastic rain jacket, undated (Box E9)
    - Vantage--Front: Vantage golf PGA tour; blue pullover windbreaker, undated (Box E9)
    - Virginia Slims--Front: Virginia Slims Series; red, undated (Box E9)
    - Virginia Slims--Front: You've come a long way baby; white, undated (Box E9)
    - Winston--Front: 16th annual Winston Smokin' Wheels Guam USA 93, The largest international motorsport event in the Pacific!; white, English and Japanese, 1993 (Box E9)
    - Winston--Front: 1988 Inaugural Seafair Performance Corner National, NHRA Winston Drag Racing Seattle Washington; sleeve: Top Eliminator SS sport service; pink (Box E9)
    - Winston--Front: Eagle, summer '92; back: Winston and eagle; white, 1991 (Box E9)
    - Winston--Front: Championship Drag Racing NHRA 29th Annual Chief Auto Parts Winternationals, Winston Drag Racing, Pomona, CA 1989; back: Budweiser king of beers 20th annual Summernationals 1989, Winston Drag Racing, Englishtown New Jersey; white (Box E9)
    - Winston--Front: Winston; back: eagle; black, undated (Box E9)
    - Winston--Front: Winston Cup 1993, Winston Cup Series Daytona '93, from Daytona to Atlanta; back: NASCAR Winston Cup Series 1993 Tour from Daytona to Atlanta, race schedule, That's worth a Winston; white (Box E9)
    - Winston--Front: Winston Cup Series Daytona; white sweat shirt, undated (Box E9)
    - Winston--Front: Winston Racing Series, stock car; white, undated (Box E9)
    - Winston--Front and back: Winston Racing Team; black and red, undated (Box E9)
  - Drinking and bar accessories, 1991-2001; undated; 179
    - Basic--Thermos, Your Basic beverage center, black, undated (Box E10)
    - Benson & Hedges--Covered drink cup, Benson & Hedges Blues, undated (Box E10)
    - Camel--Coasters, Camel since 1913 and Pleasure to Burn, 2001 (Box E10)
    - Camel--Insulated can holder, Club Camel, blue with Joe Camel, 1991 (Box E10)
    - Craven "A"--Coasters (in French), undated (Box E10)
      Text: Du 15 au 25 Juillet, Fou rire Craven A Sortez votre fou! Serie Cabaret. L'Univers Fou Craven A. Serie Club Soda. Serie Craven A Fou bars en bars. Juste pour rire
    - Dakota--Insulated mug, blue, undated (Box E10)
      Surgeon General warning label attached
    - Kool--Bar mat, Kool Filter Kings, green, undated (Box E10)
    - Kool--Can opener, Come up to Kool, white, undated (Box E10)
    - Lucky Strike--Coasters, undated (Box E10)
      Text: L.S./M.F.T. Lucky Strikes Again, The moment is right for it
    - Marlboro--Sports cup with straw, red, 1991 (Box E10)
    - Marlboro--Thermos, Coleman red and white, undated (Box E10)
    - Merit--Coasters, You've got Merit, white, undated (Box E10)
    - Multiple cigarette brands depicted on a plastic tumbler, undated (Box E10)
    - Satin--Serving tray, undated (Box E11)
      Replica of vintage advertising. Text: Satin Aristocratic in Quality Democratic in Price, Satin Turkish blend cigarettes 20 for 15cts.
    - Vantage--Insulated mug, Vantage the right light, black, 1992 (Box E10)
  - Games and sports paraphernalia, 1933-1992; undated; 180
    - Benson & Hedges--Playing cards, undated (Box E12)
    - Camel--Magician's Handy Book of Cigarette Tricks also coin and card magic, by Paul Carlton, 1933 (Box E12)
    - Camel--Playing cards, 75th birthcay, Joe Camel, 1988 (Box E12)
    - Camel--Playing cards, Club Camel, 1992 (Box E12)
    - Camel--Playing cards, The Hard Pack, 1991 (Box E12)
    - Camel--The Game (cards, dice, score pad), 1992 (Box E12)
    - Chesterfield--Bridge by Ely Culbertson (book), 1935 (Box E12)
    - Lucky Strike--Bridge game card by Milton C. Work, hand no. 45 in a series, undated (Box E12)
      Text on one side "Ok-Miss America! We thank you for your patronage; other side describes bidding systems and game play
    - Marlboro--Playing cards (menthol green), 1989 (Box E12)
    - Marlboro--Playing cards mailing, Wild West series, two packs in box, 1991 (Box E12)
    - Now--Playing cards, undated (Box E12)
    - Old Gold--Punch board game, 1940s (Box E12)
    - Player's Navy Cut--Playing cards "Player's Please", undated (Box E12)
    - Real--Playing cards, undated (Box E12)
    - Salem--Bingo game card, undated (Box E12)
    - Skoal--Playing cards, 1992 (Box E12)
    - Vantage--Golf set (tees, ball markers, spike and divot tool, undated (Box E12)
    - Virginia Slims--Playing cards, 1985 (Box E12)
  - Luggage, undated; 181
    - Camel insulated bag, Joe Camel "Smooth Character" (Box E13)
    - Camel pool cue bag, Joe Camel "Smooth Character" (Box E13)
    - Marlboro duffle (Box E13)
    - Philip Morris duffle (Box E13)
    - Salem nylon duffle (Box E14)
    - Salem pool cue bag, "Salem SoundWaves" (Box E14)
    - Vantage bag (Box E14)
    - Virginia Slims SlimSak bag in box, "You've come a long way baby" (Box E14)
    - Winston bag (Box E14)
    - Winston insulated bag with built-in radio (Box E14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988; undated; 182
    - Automobile winshield shade--Camel 75th anniversary (Box E15)
    - Badge--L&M logo (Box E15)
    - Badge--Marlboro logo (Box E15)
    - Badge--Marlboro race car (Box E15)
    - Badge--Philip Morris logo (Box E15)
    - Badge--Red Man, "America's Best Chew" (Box E15)
    - Badge--Winston Cup Series (NASCAR) (Box E15)
    - Badge--Winston eagle (Box E15)
    - Badge--Winston eagle 1 (Box E15)
    - Badge--Winston Million--Daytona, Talladega, Charlotte, Darlington (Box E15)
    - Badge--Winston, The Winston checkered flags (Box E15)
    - Bubble gum package--Big League Chew Original shredded bubble gum (1988) (Box E15)
    - Button--Accord "Ask about the Ultra-mild Taste Accord" (Box E15)
    - Button--Kool Jazz Festival (Box E15)
    - Camera--Parliament Lights, blue plastic point-and-shoot 35mm (Box E16)
    - Candy cigarette boxes; parody brands--Camal; Chesterfeeld, Lucky Stripe "It's Tasty"; Pell Mell tasty cigarettes (Box E15)
    - Cigarette/matches wall display--Kool "Light up a Kool" with penguin (Box E16)
    - Cigarette pack--Kool box replica with sticky back for display mounting (Box E16)
    - Comb--Marlboro (Box E15)
    - Decal--Lucky Strikes Again (Box E15)
    - Grocery checkout separator--Salem "natural menthol cigarettes" (Box E16)
    - Grocery checkout separator--Winston "Filter Cigarettes" (Box E16)
    - Keychain--Marlboro (Box E15)
    - Keychain--Philip Morris brands (Box E15)
    - Keychain--Winston (Box E15)
    - Letter opener--Philip Morris (Box E16)
    - Magnet--Lucky Strike vintage pack design (face only, magnet strip has been removed) (Box E15)
    - Magnet--Marlboro (Box E15)
    - Makeup applicator--Virginia Slims "You've come a long way baby" (Box E16)
    - Megaphone--Winston, Cardboard tube with slogans "Yell for your team" and "Winston tastes good like a cigarette should" (Box E16)
    - Name tag holder--Winston (Box E15)
    - Paperweight?--Camel, padlock design (Box E16)
    - Pen--Souvenir of visitor tour, R.J. Reynolds Co. (Box E16)
    - Pencil set--Philip Morris (pencils, sharpener, eraser) (Box E16)
    - Peppermint wrapper--Winston "Extra cool" made in Malang, Indonesia (Box E15)
    - Picture--Virginia Slims "Sin City" (Box E16)
    - Pin--Features Skoal, Copenhagen, Happy Days smokeless tobacco (Box E15)
    - Pin--Marlboro (Box E15)
    - Rolling paper dispenser--Vogue Pure White Papers (in English and French), wall mounting (Box E16)
    - Wallet--Marlboro (Box E16)
    - Wallet--Merit (Box E16)
    - Windshield scraper--Marlboro (Box E16)
  - Packaging (Cigar and Cigarette cartons, packs and boxes), undated; 183
    - Big Man Chewing Tobacco pouch (Box E17)
    - Free Non-Tobacco carton (Tobacco- and nicotine-free smoking product made from cocoa bean hulls) (Box E17)
    - Holland Cigars box (Slogan "Super King Size") (Box E17)
    - Honest Long Cut Smoking and chewing tobacco (Box E17)
    - Next De-Nic 100s carton (9 packs of regular and one menthol) (Box E17)
    - Red Man Totems stick of chewing tobacco (Box E17)
    - Savvy 100s carton (Box E17)
    - Tucketts Preferred cigar box (Box E17)
    - Samples of cigarette packs (Box E18)
      Includes 555 Filter Kings (Great Britain); American Blend; American Full; American Lights; American Spirit; Austin Lights; Benson & Hedges; Boots (Mexico, in Spanish); Bull Durham Lights; Camel Filters (Joe Camel collector packs); Camel Lights (Hard collector pack with 1926 ad); Camel Lights (Soft collector pack with 1934 ad; offer for vintage lighter); Cost Cutter; Dakota Lights; Daqingshan (China); Double Happiness (China); Dunhill (New Zealand); Falcon Lights; Gold Coast; Good Companion (Hong Kong); GPC Approved; Harley Davidson; Heritage Lights; Holiday (Australia; Series with various government health warnings); Hollywood (tax exempt export pack); Home Run; Hope (Japan); Jin Si Hou (China); Joy (Denmark; slogan "Joy to the World"); Kamel; Kool; Magna Lights; Maverick Specials; Mercer; New Look Light; Newport Menthol (10-cigarette sample size pack); Pall Mall; Players Extra (Canada); Players Select; Premier (Slogan "The Cleaner Smoke." Tobacco is heated, not burned); Prime Menthol; Private Stock
    - Samples of cigarette packs (Box E19)
      Includes Alas Extra (Mexico, in Spanish); Benson & Hedges (New Zealand); Carlton Soft Pack; Cartier; City 100s; Craven "A"; Dakar (Canada, with graphic health warning); Eve Lights 120s; Faros (Mexico); Full Flavor 100s; GPC Approved; Hope (Japan); Look Light 100s (Denmark); Marlboro Lights 25s; Merit Ultra Lights; Metro Menthol; Misty Menthol; Monarch Lights; Newport Stripes; Philip Morris Navy; Players 100s; Players Navy Cut; Prime 100s Lights; Pyramid Ultra; Rave; Real; Rocky Mountains (Denmark); Rothmans (New Zealand); Sigari Marconi cigars; Signature; Spring Lemon; Star (Switzerland; picture of Berlin Wall); Swisher Sweets; Tall 120s; Tourney; Triumph Menthol; U.S.A. Gold; Virginia Slims; VQ Ultra Lights (Value & Quality); West Quickies; Winston Select; Worth King Size; Yidaitianjiao (China)
  - Printed Material, 1894-2002; undated; 184
    - Calendar--Merit, 1994 (Box E20)
    - Catalog--Camel Cash vol. 2, 1992 (Box E20)
    - Catalog--Camel Cash vol. 5, 1994 (Box E20)
    - Catalog--Dakota Trading Company, 1990 (Box E20)
    - Collector cards--Silk Cut (Great Britain), 1993 (Box E20)
    - Collector cards--W.C. MacDonald (Great Britain): British Consol, Brier, 1934 (Box E20)
    - Cookbook--Benson & Hedges presents 100 of the world's greatest recipes by James Beard, 1976 (Box E20)
    - Postcards--Best of Luck Strike (Germany), 1996 (Box E20)
    - Promotion--Lucky Strike "Lucky Time" mailing, 1998 (Box E20)
    - Promotion--Lucky Strike postcards/scooter contest (Switzerland), 2002 (Box E20)
    - Promotion--Merit coffee mug offer, 1991 (Box E20)
    - Promotion--Next mailing, came with free packs, 1989 (Box E20)
    - Promotion--Salem free pouch/watch package, undated (Box E20)
    - Sign--Camel Genuine Taste, 1995-1997 (Box E20)
    - Sign--Camel license plate, 75th anniversary, 1988 (Box E20)
    - Sign--Camel menthol, 1996 (Box E20)
    - Sign--Cancer cures smoking (picture of tombstone), 1967 (Box E20)
    - Sign--No smoking, undated (Box E20)
    - Sign--Players "Say Player's Please" with strike pad, circa 1950s (Box E20)
    - Sign--Smoke Caton Quality Cigar, undated (Box E20)
    - Sign--Warning the Sugeon General has determined that warnings from the Surgeon General can be hazardous to a good time, undated (Box E20)
    - Stickers--Anti-smoking, INFACT "Stop Marketing Tobacco to Children", undated (Box E20)
    - Wall thermometer--Salem "Refresh Your Taste!", undated (Box E20)
    - Book cover--Anti-smoking: Trash Tobacco Slam the Can; Family Health Foundation of Nebraska/Nebraska DOC (Doctors Ought to Care), 2000 (Box E21)
    - Bumper stickers--Anti-smoking, INFACT "Stop Marketing Tobacco to Children", undated (Box E21)
    - Calendar--Camel, Joe Camel, 1993 (Box E21)
    - Calendar--Camel, Joe Camel Weekends, 1993 (Box E21)
    - Cigar labels, undated (Box E21)
    - Contents of binder--Anti-smoking advocacy, satire, etc., 1 of 3, 1988-2000; undated; 2 folders (Box E27)
      Materials in English, French, Russian, Icelandic, others
    - Contents of binder--Anti-smoking advocacy, satire, etc., 2 of 3, 1950s-2002; 2 folders (Box E27)
    - Contents of binder--Anti-smoking advocacy, satire, etc., 3 of 3, 1991-2000 (Box E27)
    - Contents of binder--Cartoons 1, 1951-1996; undated (Box E27)
      Includes cartoons from Bizarro, Boston Globe, Doonesbury, Financial Post, Globe and Mail, Newsweek, Sally Forth, The Far Side, The Modern World, The Nation, The Oregonian, Vancouver Sun, Washington Post
    - Contents of binder--Cartoons 2, 1987-1996; undated; 2 folders (Box E27)
    - Contents of binder--Cartoons 3, 1887-2001; 2 folders (Box E27)
    - Contents of binder--Clippings 1, 1952-1998 (Box E27)
    - Contents of binder--Clippings 2, 1991-2002 (Box E27)
    - Contents of binder--International tobacco advertisements A-C, 1925-1995 (Box E27)
      Includes 555, Alpine, Barclay, Benson & Hedges, Cambridge, Camel, Cartier, Commodore, Craven A
    - Contents of binder--International tobacco advertisements D-H, 1986-1995 (Box E27)
      Includes Davidoff, Djarum, Dunhill, Escort, Fellows
    - Contents of binder--International tobacco advertisements J-L, 1985-1995 (Box E27)
      Includes Javanese Jongens, John Player, Kent, Lord, Lucky Strike
    - Contents of binder--International tobacco advertisements M-P, 1983-2001 (Box E27)
      Includes Marlboro, Mercedes, Mild Seven, Newport, Panda, Peter Jackson, Pierre Cardin, Prince
    - Contents of binder--International tobacco advertisements P-Z, 1980-1995 (Box E27)
      Includes Rothmans, Peter Stuyvesant, Philip Morris, Salem, St. Moritz, Sterling, Summit, Superlights, Top Club, Winfield, Winston, Wills
    - Contents of binder--Smoking cessation products and methods, 1894-2002; 2 folders (Box E27)
    - Contents of binder--Spit, chew, cigars 1 of 2, circa 1900s-2000 (Box E27)
    - Contents of binder--Spit, chew, cigars 2 of 2, 1916-2000 (Box E27)
    - Contents of binder--Visual aids, 1967-2002 (Box E27)
      Includes charts, tables and other graphic materials used by Pollay in presentations and lectures
    - Promotions--Camel, Buy 2 packs and get 1 free, store display, 2000 (Box E21)
    - Promotions--Camel, Buy 2 packs get a Camel "T" free, package, undated (Box E21)
    - Promotions--Camel, Free Camel Hardpack T-shirt with 3-pack purchase, package, 1991 (Box E21)
    - Promotions--Camel, Genuine Taste tank top free with 3-pack purchase, package, undated (Box E21)
    - Promotions--Camel, Joe's Place tumbler free with 2-pack purchase, package, undated (Box E21)
    - Sign--Camel Genuine Taste, 1996 (Box E21)
    - Sign--Lucky Strike, An American Original (woman with WWII bomber), undated (Box E21)
    - Sign--Lucky Strike, Be Happy Go Lucky, Lucky Strike Means Fine Tobacco (woman with automobile), undated (Box E21)
    - Sign--Old Gold presents Babe Ruth in the blindfold cigarette test (replica of 1930 sign), 1991 (Box E21)
    - Sign--Old Gold, The favorite of the fair, wins new friends every day, undated (Box E21)
    - Shopping bag--Camel, Copenhagen Airport, undated (Box E22)
    - Shopping bag--Kent, Allders International duty free shops, undated (Box E22)
    - Shopping bag--Marlboro, undated (Box E22)
    - Shopping bag--Marlboro, Camus Cognac, Hong Kong Airport duty free shop, undated (Box E22)